<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>All Posts - malayalamozhi</title>
        <link>http://malayalamozhi.github.io/en/posts/</link>
        <description>All Posts | malayalamozhi</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>heige.pcloud@outlook.com (PCloud)</managingEditor>
            <webMaster>heige.pcloud@outlook.com (PCloud)</webMaster><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Feb 2022 18:29:04 &#43;0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://malayalamozhi.github.io/en/posts/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>Type Malayalam on Linux ibus m17n Malayalam</title>
    <link>http://malayalamozhi.github.io/en/type/</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 12 Feb 2022 18:29:04 &#43;0530</pubDate><author>
                    <name>malayalamozhi</name><uri>http://malayalamozhi.github.io/en/authors/malayalamozhi</uri></author><guid>http://malayalamozhi.github.io/en/type/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Type Malayalam on Linux without Hazzle Pacha Malayalam project has released an IBUS M17n Keyboard layout based on the ITRANS transliteration scheme. Download it here A mapping guide is included with the file you download See how to Install IBUS m17n on Linux]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Aranadan Language</title>
    <link>http://malayalamozhi.github.io/en/aranadan/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 14:19:38 &#43;0530</pubDate><author>
                    <name>Malayalamozhi</name><uri>https://malayalamozhi.github.io</uri></author><guid>http://malayalamozhi.github.io/en/aranadan/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/aranadan.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>ഏറനാടന്‍  മലയാളത്തില്‍ വായിക്കാം  Aranadan (Eranadan) is a South-Dravidian language belonging to the Malayalam group of languages. It is spoken by the Aranadan tribe in the Malappuram District of Kerala. Even though Aranadan bears many similarities with the Malayalam language, there is Kannada influence in the language.
Aranadan has no writing system of its own. However, the Malayalam script and Ponnani script (Arabi-Malayalam) are used to write this language.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Is Malayalam a mixture of Tamil and Sanskrit? Part 2</title>
    <link>http://malayalamozhi.github.io/en/malayalam-tamil/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 05 Dec 2021 10:10:13 &#43;0532</pubDate><author>
                    <name>Malayalamozhi</name><uri>https://malayalamozhi.github.io</uri></author><guid>http://malayalamozhi.github.io/en/malayalam-tamil/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/malayalamtamil.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>മലയാളത്തില്‍ വായിക്കാം! Info  Read the first part of this article by visiting this link.   Tamil and Tamilkam The whole argument about the “Tamil origin” of Dravidian languages revolves around the meaning of the word Tamil. What this word meant in the past matters a lot when we approach Dravidian linguistics. The word Tamil in a historical sense had a much more elaborative meaning and wasn&rsquo;t restricted to the boundaries of the Modern-day Indian State of Tamil Nadu.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Is Malayalam a mixture of Tamil and Sanskrit?</title>
    <link>http://malayalamozhi.github.io/en/malayalam-language/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 26 Nov 2021 10:10:13 &#43;0530</pubDate><author>
                    <name>Malayalamozhi</name><uri>https://malayalamozhi.github.io</uri></author><guid>http://malayalamozhi.github.io/en/malayalam-language/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/malayalamlang.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>മലയാളത്തില്‍ വായിക്കാം! Is Malayalam a mixture of Tamil and Sanskrit? Malayalam is the daughter of Tamil, and Sanskrit has become more of a cliché. Can one get Tamil if Sanskrit is eliminated from Malayalam? Or vice versa? This is an inquiry into the subject of whether Malayalam has its own identity or not.
Info  This article is divided into two halves as all aspects of the language need to be looked at in detail.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>nattu pattu</title>
    <link>http://malayalamozhi.github.io/en/nattu-pattu/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 10 Nov 2021 08:20:54 &#43;0530</pubDate><author>
                    <name>Malayalamozhi</name><uri>https://malayalamozhi.github.io</uri></author><guid>http://malayalamozhi.github.io/en/nattu-pattu/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/njattu-cover.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>ഞാറ്റുപാട്ട്  മലയാളത്തില്‍ വായിക്കാം  
The rhythm and melody that was once heard in the paddy fields of Kerala vanished over time. Songs were sung during planting of saplings and during harvest. These songs have played a major ruling in maintaining the uniqueness of the language and highlighting its richness. There were songs to be sung while planting the seedlings, just like the harvest songs which were sung during the harvest.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Chera Dynasty and Kerala</title>
    <link>http://malayalamozhi.github.io/en/chera/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2021 07:27:49 &#43;0530</pubDate><author>
                    <name>Malayalamozhi</name><uri>https://malayalamozhi.github.io</uri></author><guid>http://malayalamozhi.github.io/en/chera/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/chera.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>The Chera Dynasty and Kerala  മലയാളത്തില്‍ വായിക്കാം  
The Cheras were the most prominent dynasty of Kerala who were one of the mūvēntar (the three crowned rulers). This Empire was referred as Kedalaputo in the Emperor Ashoka&rsquo;s Pali edicts. Not just the mighty Ashoka Empire, but the Greeks and Romans marked the existence of this stupendous empire of Kerala.
With their Naval might, the Cheras conquered the Sea, and regimented maritime trade in the region.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Arabi Malayalam</title>
    <link>http://malayalamozhi.github.io/en/arabi-malayalam/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 07 Oct 2021 20:00:42 &#43;0530</pubDate><author>
                    <name>Malayalamozhi</name><uri>https://malayalamozhi.github.io</uri></author><guid>http://malayalamozhi.github.io/en/arabi-malayalam/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/arabi-malayalam.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>Arabi Malayalam  മലയാളത്തില്‍ വായിക്കാം  Arabi-Malayalam is a macaronic language popular among the Muslim community of Kerala, which served an import role in the spread of Islamic knowledge in Malabar. The area from Ponnani to Kasargod was the major influence zone of Arabi Malayalam. Although some sources conclude that the Arabs had trade links with Kerala even before Islam, the birth of this macaronic language and its vast literature is credited to the teachings of Islam.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Glossary</title>
    <link>http://malayalamozhi.github.io/en/glossary/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate><author>
                    <name>Malayalamozhi</name><uri>https://malayalamozhi.github.io</uri></author><guid>http://malayalamozhi.github.io/en/glossary/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Warning  Work in Progess! Add words or make corrections to the glossary   Warning  Use the Malayalam version for recent updates   Note  s. - sanskrit (s. സത്യം ) | tdbh - tadbhava തത്ഭവം (ചീരാമന്‍ t.) | eur. - european   If you are on a pc use ctrl+f to search
 അ അക - sprout അകം - inside, mind, place, house
അകം തെളിയുക - to become happy അകകുലം - sound made with a counch അകക്കണ്ണ് - wisdom അകക്കാമ്പ് - mind, heart]]></description>
</item></channel>
</rss>
